A Guide to the Papers of Julien Green, 1941-1944
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Julien Green, 1941-1944
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
9188
This collection consists of 12 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given to the library by the author on November 9, 1972.
Contents List
- Writers I Have Known, April 3, 1944, T.M.S., 17 pages [in the author's hand on page 1], with 36 holograph additions and corrections; signed on page 17.
  This manuscript is from a lecture given at Mills College, California.
- Writers I Have Known (continued), n.p., A.M.S., 11 pages in the author's hand.
- My First Book in English, May 21, 1944, T.M.S., 16 pages on carbon typescript
  This manuscript is from a lecture in Baltimore, Maryland.
- On Paris, n.p. December 1943, T.M.S., 4 pages on carbon typescript; signed on p. 4, with the note "A few more words to be added."
- How a Novelist Begins, n.p., T.M.S., 12 pages on ribbon typescript; signed on page 12.
  This script is from a lecture.
- Where Do Novels Come From, n.p., T.M.S., 4 pages on ribbon typescript; signed on page 4.
- On Keeping a Diary, July 27, 1944, T.M.S., 21 pages on ribbon typescript with 38 holograph additions and corrections; signed on page 21
  This typescript is from a lecture given at Mills College, California.
- Untitled; first line, "As I look back on the period.. .", n.p., T.M.S., 22 pages on carbon typescript; signed on page 22.
  This typescript is from a lecture.
- "America at War Speaking," text for radio broadcast, New York, December 2, 1943, A.M.S., 3 pages in French accompanied by 3 pages of mimeographed English translation with the note, "Passed Censor"
- On Paris, mimeographed verson, December 16, 1943, Five pages
  This version was at an exhibition mounted by the Coordinating Council of French Relief Societies, Inc.
- Passey, Julien Green, June 4, 1943, This item is in The Commonwealth, Vol. XXXVIII; three leaves are removed from a copy of the magazine.
- Translation and the "Fields of Scripture," Julien Green, Winter, 1941-1942, 3 pages removed from a magazine [ Reader's Digest?].
  This item is condensed from the American Scholar.